#### Contact

tristanlduffy@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tristan-duffy-4228618b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Mental Health
Psychiatric Care
Nursing

# **Tristan Duffy**

**Travel Nurse** 

Florence, South Carolina Area

## Summary

I am a Traveling Psychiatric Nurse from South Carolina. So far my adventures have led me to Oregon then Vermont, Texas, St. Louis, Tampa, Colorado, and Nebraska. I travel for the experiences, the cultures, the nature, the humans I meet, and the wild, fascinating adventure that is life- not for the money. Humans are absolutely fascinating to me, and I befriend almost every person I meet. The closer people are to our society's definition of weird or insane, the more I long to know them. Needless to say, my heart and soul is in Psychiatric nursing. Words can never express how happy I am to not only have a career doing what I love most, but to also be receiving the opportunity to make a difference in the lives of the people who touch my heart and soul the most. I am have been and will forever be working an advocate and warrior for mental health. For now, I have created a new Facebook support and educational group named "No Stigma Attached." Please feel free to join and invite others.

I believe this quote sums up why I love mental health: "One person's craziness is another person's reality." -Tim Burton.

## Experience

Advanced Travel Nursing
Travel Nurse
May 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)
Travel

No Stigma Attached Mental Health Advocate March 2016 - Present (4 years 5 months) Florence, South Carolina

No Stigma Attached© is a group focused on ending the stigma on mental health, raising awareness by educating others, and sharing ideas to aid in the fight for more mental health rights. The goal for this group is to make this a place where members can feel safe to share stories, struggles, educational

Page 1 of 6

material, and ideas that can help raise awareness for mental health and mental health rights with support and without judgment.

Let's start talking with no stigma attached.

https://www.facebook.com/groups/1070014803065250/

TravelMax
Travel Registered Nurse
June 2017 - May 2018 (1 year)
United States

Psychiatric Travel Nurse

Oregon State Hospital Agency Mental Health RN August 2017 - March 2018 (8 months) Salem, Oregon

Relief Pool/Agency RN with Maxim Healthcare.

Floating Charge Nurse to any of the 20+ psychiatric units inside the hospital. Currently working most shifts as the night shift Charge Nurse in any of the 6 units located inside the Maximum Security Program while providing interdisciplinary, therapeutic-based psychiatric treatment and promoting therapeutic-based recovery to all patients.

McLeod Health 2 years 10 months

Behavioral Health Registered Nurse March 2015 - May 2017 (2 years 3 months)

Darlington, South Carolina

Work with the treatment team to provide crisis intervention and stabilization for patients with mental disorders such as depression, schizophrenia, bipolar disorder/manic depressive illnesses, PTSD, post partum depression, grief/loss, psychosis, and substance abuse disorders.

Registered Nurse August 2014 - March 2015 (8 months) Registered Nurse on a Medical floor.

Palmetto Health Adult Behavioral Health Care Student Nurse January 2014 - May 2014 (5 months)

Page 2 of 6

columbia, south carolina area

Clinical experience

Senior Capstone Course

- # Working one-on-one with a charge nurse
- # Working one-on-one with patients with mental diseases such as PTSD, depression, Suicidal Ideation, Homicidal Ideation, Schizophrenia, Auditory Hallucinations, bipolar disorders, etc.
- # Assess patient mental status
- √#Assist with activities of daily living
- √#Make care plans for patient needs
- # Make rounds with nurse to document patient activity, mental status, and pain scale
- # Review medication information with patients
- # Give oral medications
- # Give intramuscular medications
- # Charting all assessments and documentations into computer system
- # Counsel patients during times of distress with the charge nurse
- # Admitting patients with the charge nurse
- # Discharging patients with the charge nurse
- # Will be able to perform all duties of the charge nurse by May 2014

## South Carolina Medical Endoscopy Center

GI Tech

June 2013 - May 2014 (1 year)

Columbia, South Carolina Area

Clinical GI Tech Job Description:

Recover patients during the post-operatative time after colonoscopies and endoscopies.

Record vital signs

Take IV's out

Clean and sanitize beds, vital sign machines, heart monitor cords, pulse oximeters, and blood pressure cuffs

Make follow up phone calls

Office Job description:

Help make patient charts

Help file patient information and charts

Help organize files

Send follow up letters for patients who are due for colonoscopies and endoscopies

#### Typed up pathology reports

Lexington Medical Center Medical-Surgical Student Nurse August 2013 - November 2013 (4 months)

columbia, south carolina area

#### Clinical Experience

- # Head to toe assessments of patients
- # Assess patients for specific complications related to diagnoses
- # Provide oral medications
- # Perform intramuscular and subcutaneous injections
- # Start IV injections under supervision of a registered nurse
- # Give IV medications including piggyback medications
- # Assist with activities of daily living
- # Formulate care plans for patients with various diseases
- # Assess and clean postoperative wounds
- # Assess pressure ulcers, clean, and re-dress the ulcers
- # Assess, clean, and change colostomy bags
- # Chart all assessments and documentations into computer system

Providence Hospitals Cardiac Student Nurse January 2013 - April 2013 (4 months)

Columbia, South Carolina Area

#### Clinical Experience

- # Acquire vital signs for preoperative and postoperative patients
- # Assess patients for postoperative and wound complications
- # Assess patients for medical diagnosis complications
- # Provide oral medications
- # Perform intramuscular and subcutaneous injections
- # Start IV's under supervision of a registered nurse
- # Assist patients with activities of daily living
- # Formulate care plans for patients
- # Assess and clean postoperative wounds

Wm. Jennings Bryan VA Hospital Psychiatric Student Nurse January 2013 - April 2013 (4 months)

columbia, south carolina area

- # Perform assessments of veterans with psychiatric disorders such as PTSD, depression, Suicidal Ideation, Homicidal Ideation, Schizophrenia, Auditory Hallucinations, bipolar disorders, etc.
- # Therapeutically communicate with the mentally ill
- # Formulate care plans and assessments for patients

#### Palmetto Health

Orthopedic Student Nurse

August 2012 - November 2012 (4 months)

Columbia, South Carolina Area

#### Clincal Experience

- # Acquired vital signs for preoperative and postoperative patients
- # Assessed patients for postoperative wound complications
- # Performed intramuscular and subcutaneous injections
- # Provided oral medications
- #Assessed and changed wound dressings
- # Assisted patients in need with activities of daily living
- # Formulated care plans for patients
- # Documented vital signs and patient notes into the computer
- # Observed surgical procedures

#### Moss Pharmacy

Medication Deliverer/ Clerk

August 2009 - August 2011 (2 years 1 month)

Florence Area, South Carolina

#### Job description:

- -Delivered medicine to patients who could not leave their homes
- -Delivered medicine to patients in nursing homes
- -Ran the cash register
- -Delivered money to the bank
- -Counted the money drawer
- -Locked all doors once business hours ended
- -Helped re-stock shelves
- -Filed patient information
- -Cleaning duties such as sweeping, vacuuming, mopping, taking out the trash, and washing pharmaceutical dishes

#### Harvest Hope Food Bank

Volunteer

August 2010 - November 2010 (4 months)

Columbia Area, South Carolina

## Education

University of South Carolina-Columbia
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2010 - 2014)